partycheap.com 2019-06-08

# Privacy Policy - PartyCheap

## TOPICS

  * INTRODUCTION
  * YOUR CONSENT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
  * WHAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY DOES AND DOES NOT COVER
  * WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION WE MAY ASK YOU TO PROVIDE
  * INFORMATION WE COLLECT USING TECHNOLOGY
  * HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
  * WHY AND WITH WHOM WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION
  * HOW WE PROTECT PERSONAL INFORMATION
  * HOW LONG DO WE KEEP PERSONAL INFORMATION?
  * HOW TO OPT OUT OF OUR DIRECT MARKETING COMMUNCIATIONS
  * CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS FOR CONSUMERS
  * MAKING REQUESTS ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
  * INTERNATIONAL VISITORS AND CUSTOMERS
  * HOW TO CONTACT US
  * CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

### INTRODUCTION

PartyCheap.com ("we," "us," "our") wants the visitors to our websites and our customers (“you” or “your”) to understand how we collect, use and disclose your information.   
The website covered by this Privacy Policy is: [ www.partycheap.com ](http://www.partycheap.com/) (our “Website”). 

### YOUR CONSENT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Please read our Privacy Policy carefully. When you use our Websites, you signify to us that you have read, understand, and agree to this Privacy Policy and that you also consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

You should not submit information to us either through our Website or other avenues if you do not agree to the terms of our Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions displayed our Website. 

### WHAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY DOES AND DOES NOT COVER

Personal information. This Privacy Policy covers personal information we obtain when you visit our Website or communicate with us in other ways. The term “personal information”, as used in this Privacy Policy, refers to information that can be used to identify an individual, directly or indirectly, alone or together with other information. Personal information also includes information about your use of our Website but does not identify you as an individual, either directly or indirectly; your use of our Website could consist of things such as your browser type, the previous web site you visited, your internet connection, and/or the equipment you use to access our Website. We will not sell or rent your personal information to anyone. 

With your consent, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about promotions, new products, or services. We do not knowingly collect or store any personal information from children except as permitted by applicable law. Other websites are not covered. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information that you provide to third parties through their applications or websites, including those you may access from links posted on our Web Site. We are not responsible for information you provide to third parties. These third parties should have their own privacy policies, which we encourage you to read before you provide information to them. 

De-identified information is not covered. We may create de-identified data from personal information by excluding data components (such as your name, email address, or linkable tracking ID) that make the data personally identifiable to you using technical means. Our use of de-identified information is not subject to this Privacy Policy. 

### WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION WE MAY ASK YOU TO PROVIDE

If you submit an order or register for our email newsletter, we will ask for the following information as applicable to your specific request: 

  * Contact name
  * E-mail address
  * Phone number(s)
  * Company name 
  * Mailing address
  * Billing address
  * Payment (credit card) information
  * Shipping information for orders and marketing materials

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT USING TECHNOLOGY

#### Data collected when you access our Website

We want you to be aware that our Website uses cookies and other tracking technologies to collect data about your visits to our Website, the devices you use, and your online activities. PartyCheap.com, and third parties we authorize, collect this information by placing cookies and other tracking devices on your computer when you access our Website. Some of the data is stored, logged and correlated with other information to analyze how our Website is used, to enable some functions to work effectively, and to develop marketing programs. Cookies used on our website expire within 72 hours. For information about controlling this data collection, see “Restricting the Use of Information Collected Using Technology” below. 

#### The types of data collected using these technologies include: 

  * Identification – date and time of your visits to our Websites, your user name and password if you establish a customer account, transaction and account history, and other personalized services and registrations;
  * Device – your IP address, internet domain name, browser type, operating system, mobile network, device telephone number;
  * Usage – website visited before our Websites, pages visited on our Websites and time spent on each pager, number and duration of visits and history of the pages viewed, and other internet activities; and
  * Location – your general geographic location as determined by your IP address and more specific location if the Websites are accessed from a mobile device (unless blocked).

For more information about these online technologies, how they work, and why we use them, see “Why and With Whom We Share Information.” Restricting the Use of Information Collected Using Technology 

You can control how cookies and other technologies are used to track and log your online activities in several ways: 

  * Managing the preference settings on your browser and device;
  * Communicating directly with Google as explained at: <https://policies.google.com/privacy;>
  * Purchasing a utility from an independent software provider that you install on your computer browsers to make website visits anonymous;
  * Visiting [www.aboutads.info/choices](https://www.aboutads.info/choices) to learn more about personalized advertising and how to opt-out of personalized advertising on your web browser and mobile apps by companies participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance.

If you restrict the use of cookies and other technologies, you will not be able to utilize some of the features of our Website including the shopping cart and Diamond Rewards Club. 

### HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We use your personal information in these ways: 

  * Process, fulfill, and contact you about your requests and orders;
  * Administer your customer account;
  * Issue invoices and process payments;
  * Send you e-mails, e-newsletters, personalized offers and other direct communications about our products, services, and promotions (for information about stopping these messages, see “How to Opt Out of Our Direct Marketing Communications”); 
  * Analyze statistical, demographic and marketing data about the visitors to our Websites with the help of data analytics and internet advertising services in order to develop our products and services, determine the effectiveness of marketing campaigns, and predict customer interests in new products;
  * Combine the information you give us and information collected through accessing our Websites with information available from our records and other sources to better understand the demographics, interests, and concerns of our customers; and
  * Protect and secure our Websites and network infrastructure by blocking and controlling disruptive use and deploying system safeguards.

How we use your personal information is subject to the following limitations:   
(1) this Privacy Policy;   
(2) any terms applicable to the services or actions you request;   
(3) any instructions you give us to limit the use of your information; and   
(4) the requirements of applicable law. 

### WHY AND WITH WHOM WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION

Service providers   
We share information with service providers (including payment processors, e-commerce CMS service providers, customer data managers, direct e-mail marketing vendors, and search engine optimization providers) who perform administrative and technology functions on our behalf. In some situations, the service provider needs your personal information in order to perform the service, such as processing a credit card payment, and they do not retain, share, store or use the cardholder’s personal information for any secondary purpose beyond processing the charge. In other situations, the service provider may have technical access to your information but does not use the information in order to perform the contract service, such as hosting an application or database or providing network infrastructure support. We require our service providers who have any access to personal information to use and protect personal information in accordance with the standards of this Privacy Policy. These companies are not allowed to use this personal information for their own marketing or commercial purposes or any purpose other than to provide the services we engage them to perform. 

Data Analytics and Internet Advertising/Marketing   
We share and allow Google Analytics and Google Ads to collect usage and device data when you access our Websites. Google uses this data to provide statistical and marketing analysis Google also aggregates the data—in de-identified form—obtained from our Website for its own use. Google represents that it builds its statistical databases and facilitates placement of targeted and personalized ads without revealing any personal information that identifies you. We also work with internet advertising companies to show you advertisements about our products when you visit other websites. This form of advertising can be based on either specific data gathered about your interests from tracking your internet usage, or from general information based on the websites you visit. 

To learn more about how Google collects and processes data from websites for data analytics and advertising purposes, please visit: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>.  
To learn more about the controls Google offers to manage the collection and use of your personal information, please visit: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>.  
To opt of out being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, please visit: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. 

Legal Protection and Compliance.  
We will disclose personal information in order to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of PartyCheap.com, our customers and others; enforce our contracts or policies including the Terms and Conditions of our Websites, and to investigate and prevent fraud. We will share personal information if we reasonably believe disclosure is necessary to comply with a law, court order, or government or regulatory request, and when required by law for other purposes. Business Changes or Transactions. Subject to appropriate confidentiality protections, we will disclose personal information to prospective transaction parties and their advisors in connection with a business transaction such as a financing, reorganization, merger, acquisition, or business sale or transfer. 

### HOW DO WE PROTECT PERSONAL INFORMATION?

We use commercially reasonable organizational, technical, and physical safeguards to protect your personal information and to meet the standards of this Privacy Policy. 

Still, we cannot and do not guarantee the security of your personal information from unauthorized use or alteration, and there is always a risk inherent in the electronic communication and storage of information (including without limitation from unauthorized entry or use, telecommunication issues, hardware or software failure, and other factors). 

Wherever we collect sensitive information, that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon in the URL field and looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page where secure information is collected.

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also take steps to protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (e.g. billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. 

### HOW LONG DO WE KEEP PERSONAL INFORMATION?

We retain personal information for as long as we reasonably require it for legal or business purposes. When we no longer have a legitimate business interest in keeping your personal information, we securely delete or destroy it. In determining data retention periods, PartyCheap.com takes into consideration applicable laws, contractual obligations, and what we reasonably believe are your expectations and requirements. For example, if you open an account or submit a request, we will retain your contact and preference information for marketing purposes until we take note that you no longer show interests in our products or services or you direct us not to continue sending our materials to you. 

### HOW TO OPT OUT OF OUR DIRECT MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS

You can opt out from receiving emails, calls, or texts from PartyCheap.com by:   
• Email—You can choose not to receive our email messages by either (1) following the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each email we send you, or (2) emailing us at [info@partycheap.com](mailto:info@partycheap.com%22), or (3) writing to us at PartyCheap.com, 1 Beistle Plaza, Shippensburg, PA 17257.   
• Mail or phone—You can opt out of mail or telephone solicitations by either (1) emailing us at [info@partycheap.com](mailto:info@partycheap.com%22), or (2) writing to us at PartyCheap.com, 1 Beistle Plaza, Shippensburg, PA 17257. 

### CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS FOR CONSUMERS

Under California’s "Shine the Light" law, California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us, once per calendar year, information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the year immediately prior to the current calendar year. To obtain this information from us, please send an email message to [info@partycheap.com](mailto:info@partycheap.com%22) with "Request for California Privacy Information" on the subject line and in the body of your message. We will provide the requested information to you at your e-mail address in response. Not all information sharing is covered by the "Shine the Light" requirements and only information on covered sharing (if any) will be included in our response. Note that our Web Site does not respond to “do not track” requests. 

### INTERNATIONAL VISITORS AND CUSTOMERS

PartyCheap.com operates in the United States and follows the information and consumer protection laws of the United States and its individual states. If you reside or are located in a different country, the data protection laws of that country may differ as to what, and how, personal information is protected. We want you to understand that when you provide your personal information to us, or we obtain it through our website or other communications with us, you consent to our processing your information in the United States, subject to United States laws, and as explained in this Privacy Policy. However, we also respond to requests you may have about your personal information as explained below. 

### MAKING REQUESTS ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

If you contact us for any of the reasons listed below, we will make a prompt and reasonable effort to honor your request:   
• To opt out of direct marketing communications;   
• To find out what personal information we have about you or request a readable copy;   
• To ask us to limit how we use your personal information;   
• To ask us to correct personal information we have about you;   
• To object to our further use of your personal information;   
• To advise us about a complaint regarding how we handle your personal information; and   
• To ask us to delete the personal information we have about you. If you wish to make a request regarding those matters, please contact us as described below. 

### NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We will notify you of changes to this Privacy Policy by updating the Privacy Policy posted on our Website and we will also contact you by email if you are on our email contact list. 

## Questions and feedback

We welcome your questions, comments, and concerns about privacy. Please send us any and all feedback pertaining to privacy, or any other issue. 

## Terms and Conditions

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website.

## Your consent

By using our site, you consent to our privacy policy.
